Muhammed Adel

Junior Software Engineer

muhammeddadel@gmail.com +201019265177 Website LinkedIn GitHub

Summary

Experienced Full stack Developer (Front End Enthusiast). Proficient in React.js, Node.js, JavaScript and other languages. With a solid background of OOP and Data structures. Got recognized by my managers as an exceptional team player and I strive to be. Proven my ability to effectively self-manage and self-learn to achieve my goals.

Experience

Full Stack Developer — IBM

02/2022 - Present

- Collaborated with the logistics team to significantly enhance the customer support tools by 85%.
- Implemented a React Application for authenticated users to submit and track support tickets.
- Provided access control to allow support agents to manage tickets and managers to track their progress.
- Managed Tracking Docs loaded from the Cloudant DB using Redux Toolkit and React states.
- Ensured authentication using Passport.js with IBM OIDC SSO.
- Created a generic React component to provide autocompletion and ensure validity of IBM emails, which can be used in any React Application developed by IBM.

Web Development Intern — IBM

08/2021 - 02/2022

- Developed a functional React App that automates the process of report generation by selecting client and date range to generate a PDF report containing Charts and Metrics of the tickets submitted by that client.
- Participated in the R&D process by researching the best approaches to implement.
- Created backend web services to retrieve and filter data using Node.js, Express.js, and DB2.

Education

Alexandria University, Faculty of Engineering, Bachelor's Degree

09/2016 - 07/2021

Major: Computer and Communications Engineering

Coursework: Algorithms, Data Structures, Database, Computer Architecture and Microprocessors

Certifications

Cloud Application Developer 2019 - Mastery Award | Badge Issued by IBM

10/2020 - 12/2020

Skills & Abilities

- React.js
- JavaScript
- MySQL .Java
- Node.js
- **HTML**
- Git
- Python
- Redux.js
- CSS
- OOP
- MongoDB
- Redux Toolkit
- **SASS**
- **Data Structures**
- Cloudant
- Next.js
- Tailwind CSS **Design Patterns**

Selected Projects

Social Media Management Platform | Graduation Project

09/2020 - 07/2021

- Collaborated with graduation team to create micro-services-based application.
- Used Facebook, Twitter, Instagram APIs to organize campaigns statistics and analyze posts performance.
- Produced behavioral and structural UML diagrams to arrange our requirements and implementations.

Arabic Joke Generator | Link

11/2021 - 11/2021

- Created Restful API that provides 100+ Arabic jokes using Node.js and MongoDB Atlas as a NoSQL db.
- Designed single page application with 5 main features using ReactJS.
- Deployed and maintained the react application on Heroku.

Redux-Movie-App | Link

01/2022 - 01/2022

- Developed a web application that integrates with IMDB API to retrieve all movies and TV shows.
- Fetched data using Redux Thunks then stored the results in a Redux State to manipulate it using Reducers.
- Performed Searching and filtering features by local states and react hooks.